What's up, everybody? Welcome to the
Titanium Vault. I'm your host, RJ Bayse
III, and today is a very special day
because we are here with our good friend
Joe Fells. And Joe and I are not only
going to be podcasting, but we're going
to be drinking beer while doing it.
What's up, Joe?
Here, here. Give me a beer.
There you go. What did you say you're
drinking over there? American water?
This is American water, also known as
Miller Lite.
There you go.
How does an immigrant invented the best
like really people talk [__] This is
the best Pilsner after you can drink
this all day.
And then I
Right here.
I'm not going to lie. When I'm at hockey
tournaments and stuff, that's what I
drink, but tonight we're we're rocking
the Ein Stök. My Viking beard, it's got
to match the beard, you know? So.
I'll uh
Like you you wouldn't catch me turning
down a Viking beer of any kind ever.
Bro, it's it's tasty. You'll like it.
So
Not at all.
For the people that don't know who you
are,
and I know you got a lot to tell today.
Tell us what it is that you do in real
estate and how did you get started?
Um
So currently as it pertains to real
estate, I have a real estate brokerage
that I Well, let me say I co-own a real
estate brokerage, a wholesaling and
acquisitions company,
uh and a a little hedge fund here in
Augusta.
There you go.
Then personally, just just Joe Fells, I
own uh Creative Construction Solutions,
licensed builder and electrician, so
full construction company in Augusta,
pretty good reputation.
Um
I also have uh my own portfolio of
65-ish properties. Uh
rental properties, there's a couple
flips in there, a couple bare lots, buy
and hold stuff, but few Airbnbs,
Georgia, Tennessee, Washington state. I
uh closed my South Carolina branch after
me and the HOA in Beaufort didn't get
along.
Um
Um and uh
pretty much if you're in Augusta,
Georgia, uh if you want to buy a house
on market, sell a house on market, lease
a house, if you want to rent a house, uh
if you want to get one off market, sell
one off market, renovate one, fix one,
you got busted by the If you have a
house in Augusta, Georgia, there's
really nothing I can't do to help you.
There you go. So, how did you get
started? How did you get into real
estate? Cuz I know you got a hell of a
story, so let's get into it.
Um man, I I
I I bought a house. Um I was
fresh out of prison and living in my
mama's basement. Um
And I literally asked her, you know,
going literally going off of a adage of
Marvin Piermont, you know, if you ain't
got your money for it, you don't need
it. I said, "Mama, Dad, let me live here
until I can buy a house."
You know, and that's kind of a
bold statement, you know, I didn't have
a driver's license. You know, I was a
eight-time convicted felon out on
parole.
Uh I'd spent, you know, 2 years before I
went to prison as a fugitive, you know,
I ran away. Uh and I I was gone. They
didn't know if I was alive or dead, and
then I was in prison, and now I'm in
their house in my mama's basement on
Sandy Run Court. Um
telling them, "Hey, let me live here
till I can buy a house." And
you're probably thinking like a
a nice house, like a house house.
I was talking about buying like a a
house-like product.
Like, you know, a some assembly
required. Um
And I did, man. I The first house I
bought was on Old Louisville Road, right
up from the jail in Augusta, man, and it
was listed for 19,000 bucks. It became a
bidding war, and I shot for the fences,
dog. 199.
Cash money.
No $20,000 loan here, baby. And uh you
know, I got it, man. I got it. It's
currently worth about 165 and it's
rented for
1250.
Wow.
Great deal.
First house I ever bought.
Listen, Georgia is one of my favorite
markets and we've done quite a few deals
in the Augusta market. So I know those
got numbers exist out there in quite a
bit. What about I mean so you're
eight-time convicted felon, you're
you're living in your mom's basement.
You said, "Hey, let me live here until I
can buy a house." What led you to real
estate? Why was that the the thing?
Well,
so I wasn't per se looking for real
estate, but that segued me into buying
the house.
Got you.
I knew I wanted to buy the house because
I didn't want to live in my parents'
basement.
Right.
I was I was fresh out the chain gang. I
was trying to,
you know, get somewhere, dog.
Right.
And uh
I
I just knew I needed a house. The real
estate portion came from, you know, I
had started my own little business and I
was doing all this contract work for
Ashcroft Properties who had between two
and 250 Section 8 rentals. And so really
the seed was planted there. You know,
I say I tell people all the time, you
will learn best through osmosis. Take
your ass somewhere and your brain will
follow. And I was with people who were
actively making money in real estate and
so I laid down with dogs and caught
fleas, basically. It jumped on my mind
and you know,
it was planted.
And once I went with it, you know, I
bought this house and I wasn't thinking
turn it into a rental. I was thinking
don't pay to live.
Right.
Uh that's all I was thinking, freedom.
Well, once I bought it, when I was
remodeling it, I saw this other house
right up the road. And it was a big
two-car garage, I mean, acre lot,
two-car garage. Dude, and it was it was
wrecked. It was [__] over the dog. It
was in bad bad shape and uh
it was just perfect for me.
They
they had to sell it real bad. I wind up
buying it for $13,000.
Oh.
Literally, I got into real estate
because a house had a bigger yard.
There you go.
I mean,
I a blind hog find an acorn every now
and again, dog. What you want to say?
Right.
So, you bought that one for 13 cuz it
had the bigger yard. So, now you're
moving out of the the $20,000 house.
No, I I actually never lived there. I
had it almost all the way done. Like and
I came back and I remember my girlfriend
at the time, later to be wife, now
ex-wife,
she had to move out of her house. Her
lease was up and
and I had bought this house. We
literally came back from a family beach
trip and
went and got all of her stuff and moved
it into this house. It was wrecked.
There was a hole in the floor where the
termites had eaten up through the
hardwoods. Like that bad. There was a
possum nest under the sink. Like it had
leaked and rotted out. Dude, this thing
was wrecked, but the air conditioner
worked.
Um I wasn't
I wasn't a heat and air guy. I didn't
know I didn't have the AC going in the
other one and it worked here and so we
just brought a mattress and put it on
the floor, man.
Um and I I came in here and I literally,
dude, I fixed this house up. The first
thing I learned is the sewer line was
bad after I spent six days gutting the
bathroom to the dirt and putting it
back. The toilet flushed for a day and a
half, then I had to replace the sewer
line and
you know, I basically I was living in
this house and I had another house. And
so, what do you do if you have an empty
house?
You do something with it, dog. You don't
just let it sit. So, you I I rented it.
And that that was the beginning of an
empire.
I love it. I love it, man, and
you know, I talked to you before
you know, the podcast and I was saying,
"Hey, man, I similar start where you
know, we were contractors and then we
started getting hired by investors."
Mhm.
And it was the same thing. It was like,
"Hold on, I'm I'm on the wrong side of
this game.
I'm doing all this work and he's making
all the money. Like, what am I doing
this for? I need to go buy the houses
and then still do the work." So, it
sounds like we had similar paths there
at the beginning where from the
contractor side of things. So, when you
were doing that work, is that kind of
like what spurred you to keep it on as
rentals or were you immediately thinking
like, "Man, I should flip these and make
big paydays?"
Well, no. I I didn't flip like
I did not flip a house as far as like
buy to sell
Right.
for
[__] I had almost
I had 10 or 12 paid for rentals before I
flipped my first house.
That's crazy.
Joe, I I mean, like quite honestly, I
don't know if you understand like how
rare that is.
Well, well, here's the thing, dog. I
really did.
Um and what most people don't comprehend
there is that I grew up without a TV.
I was born in Papua New Guinea. My
parents are missionaries. I was I was in
a church. We had a prayer hike every
morning, every night. I didn't have a
TV.
I was kicked out of UGA my second
semester for selling dope. Give me a
little taste of freedom. I'm right back
home. I was gone, man. I was a fugitive
in the streets for 2 years then in the
in prison and I literally got out and
started working, going to Alcoholics
Anonymous, and running trails. And that
was all I did for a decade.
That's it. That was it. And so,
I've never really stopped to look at
anything. If you see how I live now,
bro, I'm not looking at [__] now. I'm
just going and doing. I never stopped to
really consider.
And I'd lived in a cave my whole life.
It was just me and the people I
surrounded myself with, with which were
all of my choosing and all of my
training. You should see the guys that
work for me. They're [__] sharp. And
uh
my family is just so gangster, dude.
Like, I didn't know it because if you're
born in a dark closet, that's all you
know, but I was always the black sheep
and the [__] up of my family. I mean,
look at my story. I've been in three
psychiatric lockups. And so, I've been,
you know, my whole life I've never felt
like I
accomplished anything at all.
I mean, until maybe
a year and a half ago.
I've won 40 and 50-mi foot races and
bought and sold 100 houses without the
use of a mortgage.
And you know, I've never really
considered it an accomplishment because
you can do all you [__] want to and
all it leads to is more longing for the
next accomplishment, dog. It's all smoke
and mirrors.
I got to ask you about that because
like, I I just became aware of you. And
like, the background story of this is
a couple years ago, I went and I grabbed
a 19-year-old at a a local real real
estate meetup.
And I said, "Why are you here?" And he
said, "I want to learn how to do real
estate. I I don't really know what this
wholesaling thing is, but I think it
sounds like something I want to do." And
I said, "Well, you can either come work
for me or you're a little punk-ass [__]
and you really don't want to learn how
to do this."
And he came over and he worked for me.
So, here we are 3 years later.
He comes in my office the other night
and he says, "Hey, do you know who Joe
Fells is?"
I said, "I don't." And he said, "Dude,
you need to get him on your podcast."
So, I messaged you that night and I
said, "Hey, man, you want to drink some
beers and shoot the shit?" And you said,
"You had me at drinking beers and
shooting the shit."
What is a podcast?
But here we are, right? And then and I
share that because
I didn't do a whole lot of background on
you, but I watched your social media. We
talked on the phone the other day.
You seem like a uh really well-spoken. I
I mean
you're a character.
But
Yeah. Yeah.
But but you're really well-spoken. You
seem like you're like super intelligent.
So, when you're talking about
three times in psychiatric wards, eight
time felon, like what was going on in
your life that caused you to to go
through those issues?
Okay, and that's the thing, man. It
I live my life and always have by a
different motivation system than almost
any other human I've ever met.
That's why, man. Is is That's why I
break algorithms is you put me in All
you see on the internet is my daily
life.
Right.
Hell, they thought Albert Einstein was
[__] for years.
Yeah, it is.
what I'm saying. And and I'm not saying
I'm him at all, but what I'm saying is
my brain
the things that are coming into my eyes
are the same [__] that's coming into
your eyes, but once it That's That's
where it stops, man. Like
and when I was a kid, man, I think I was
about I was a junior senior in high
school, man, and I was on a wrestling
team, dude. I wrestled 119 lb, and I was
I was good at it. Um I'd do anything to
make weight. Run in a sauna in a trash
bag in front of little Asian ladies at
the Y.
Um dude, I I go make myself retch after
Thanksgiving dinner. Anything. Um and it
was around that time I started waking up
in the middle of the night, man, at like
2:00 or 3:00 in the morning. Just boom,
ready to go, and I'd go run. I'd go run
around the neighborhood, right there on
Sandy Run Court, uh all around
Montclair. And one night my dad had like
a
uh premonition. He'd always wake up and
check on us. I'm a father now. If you've
got kids, you know, you do it all the
time.
And he went down there just to look, and
I was gone.
Now,
back then I was like that. I just went
on a run. Now, you to think this is in
like
2002, 2003. There was cell phones. I'm
just gone.
Right.
Freaked out and after I came back,
they're like, "What happened?" I was
like, "I what? I woke up to and went for
a run."
They're like, "Wow."
Okay, you know, between that and the the
sweat bags and the won't eat and the
vomiting, we just need to get this kid
looked at.
And, you know, I've I've been in a
number of times and and they put me on
medication. Dog, ain't nothing wrong
with me.
Right.
Uh-uh.
You didn't deserve a verse. I mean, you
wanted to succeed at what you were
doing. I mean
Yeah.
We were talking about the other night.
You're like, bro, I I don't even know
what I'm doing with this social media
stuff, but I'm just it's working.
Dude, yeah, I don't Every video you
Every single video you see on the
internet has been recorded, edited,
posted
by me. I've hashtagged every single one.
Myself. In my
Hold on. Remember all that other [__] I
said I own?
Yeah.
Like, I do that and I also do this all
at the same time, man, and that's just
how I am. Um you know, I I I competed
and trained and ran all these ultra
marathons. I've won some 40 and
50-milers.
You know, I'm I'm up at 6:30 in the
morning. Um
you know, I'm I am I do not live a cushy
lifestyle.
To quote Matt Brown, the UFC fighter, I
live my life in misery. Like
Like, I take that you know, most people
would never know it by by looking at me,
but I'm a
huge fan and follower of Jesus. Like, I
just understand him differently than
y'all do. And that man literally told me
two things. Take up your cross, your
instrument of torture, daily, and follow
me. And I happen to be an itinerant
carpenter who lives in a van going
around doing nice things for people.
I don't know. I'm just trying to follow
this dude. And another thing he told me
is if you don't
uh a sword, sell your cloak and buy one.
And like so I I live by these things,
man, and you can tell. Um and you know,
I it it's led to a lot of success in
real estate, man, but if you apply these
principles to pretty much anything,
you'll be successful.
Look at social media.
I love that, man. I mean, let let me ask
you this cuz
you started buying houses, like you
bought those those first couple what I
call [__] boxes, right? 19,000, 13,000,
and now they're worth something, right?
But
did you ever
educate yourself on what you were doing
with real estate or was it always just
like, "Hey, buy cheap and you know, fix
it up and it's worth more."
All right, so so that's the thing, man,
like
when you say educate yourself, I have
never
listened to a podcast of any kind.
The second podcast I've ever interacted
with, we recorded the other one last
week. Uh I've never read a book on
investing. The only self-help book I've
ever used is a calculator.
I mean, it's pretty basic. My rule of
thumb all these years has just been
redneck real estate, dog. Gross numbers.
I'm not You You can run all your
vacancy, blah blah. Look,
if I can get 2% gross return a month,
I'll buy it.
If I can buy this house for 20 and put
20 in it and have 40 in it and rent it
for 800, it's a go.
There you go.
Now, you
You You can factor in all that vacancy
and the If them numbers hit, you good,
dog.
There you go. And I agree with that. I
mean, because there is this like in the
nicer neighborhoods, people talking
about 1% rentals. They They don't cash
flow. They don't cash flow worth [__]
You know, that it don't work. 2% is
where you got to be minimally in most
neighborhoods, and I agree with that.
Now, let's let's talk about, you know,
finding properties cuz dude, I educate
and this is what I am literally
educating thousands of people on how to
do real estate. And they like struggle
with figuring out, how do I find
motivated sellers? How do I talk to
them? What paperwork do I use? Like, how
do you figure all this [__] out?
Well, buying houses.
Um
find the houses to buy?
Okay, the best leads I've ever gotten
are organic. That's a no-brainer.
Right.
Um I'm going to start out by saying
deals beget deals. The more deals you
do, the more deals that find their way
into your lap. And you know, just that's
how I got the the majority of them.
I've only bought
maybe seven or eight houses off the
market my entire life.
I don't buy on market. Um
I marketed I started, you know, doing
wholesaling. I was marketing direct to
seller. Just myself sending mailers,
cold calling, driving for dollars. You
know, I was getting my feet wet. I see a
house over here, write down the address,
go put a little note on the door.
You know, hey, I was a young hungry kid
[__] hustling. That's what I was. And
that's the thing, man. You know, I might
I've always done what I thought was my
job.
But what it really was a lot of times
was the training for my next job.
Like, yeah, I was out there hustling. I
was learning what didn't work. And I was
learning how the system worked. How you
found data and how you tracked down
people and, you know, oh god, that's the
Shelf Corporation. I wonder who I talk
to at the Shelf Corporation. You know,
like you know, hey, you you learn to
weed out entities pretty quick.
Yeah.
You chase your tail long enough. It's
like watching the Animal Planet, dude.
You you see the little bears trying to
catch them at the river. That's what I
was doing, man.
I love it. I love it, man. And listen,
you are a testament for
instead of analysis paralysis, sitting
down, reading the books, listening to
podcasts, and all this [__] You
just went out there and started taking
action and next thing you know, you're
like, "Dude, I'm
I'm a millionaire like I own all these
properties
at 2% rentals all over the place in
Augusta, Georgia."
Like you're talking about your own [__]
in Washington state. I got to ask you
about that later. I don't even
understand why that
Ooh. Hey, you're going to come there,
ain't you?
I'll I'll do it if you invite me.
All right, hey hey, we can drink beer on
my porch and look at the Olympic
mountains and there's your choice of
legal shops everywhere. We can go to the
beach in 9 minutes from my house or to
Olympic National Park in 15. My neighbor
Gary grew up in in Alaska building
pipelines. Just sit here and talk to
Gary, man. Come to the Sea Shack.
I love it. So, the you're one of Justin
one of the things that Justin said,
dude. You got to talk to this guy. He
bought like a van or a school bus or or
both or something like this and it's
like what you live in or what you
working out of or some [__] What's the
story? What what's going on? What what
what you got? A van or a school bus?
So, well,
I live in El Suave, which is a 1999
Dodge wide body Explorer. Um I like my
vans like I like my hips, wide body.
Look at Alex.
Um
and uh
Uh sorry, uh we were flagged for hate
speech. They do that all the time. Um
I uh
I man literally, man, in
May of '22, I was about at a breaking
point, man. You know, I was I'd been
sober for 12 years. I sponsored people.
I was married. I had two kids. I'd done
everything that society told me to be
happy and I was absolutely miserable. I
did this [__] at a high level, a really
high level.
And you know,
I I uh
I damn I was miserable, man. And so, I
literally I I was getting divorced. I
pretty much left my company to Brandon
and the guys and said, "Here, guys.
Here's a full-fledged construction
company. Do what you want to with it." I
was done. Literally done.
Um and I bought El Suave. I spent some
months fixing it up, putting solar on
it. And I literally I bought this house
out on the West Coast. And I needed and
I said, "Fuck it. I'm gone. I'm gone,
dude." I cried my eyes out, dude. I'll
cry talking about it, man. Just
[__] it, man. I I literally said, "Fuck
it." and left in that van and drove
across the country looking for the soul
of America, man. I done everything y'all
told me to. I beat you at it and I'm
[__] miserable. I'm screaming without
a mouth.
And so, that's what I did, man. I did
that and I drove across the country,
man. Met Alex along the way on Tinder.
And who had a school bus.
Who had a school bus. Interesting how
this all works. It was then It was
literally on this trip when I got social
media.
That's literally when it started.
I didn't have any social media for 7
years.
Right.
And so, it just started there, man. And
uh
So, I live in the van, dude. I drove all
the way I've driven the whole country
coast to coast four times.
Uh
I have an off-grid uh generator in
there. Pushes 240 V. It's a 6 kW
inverter. You know, I backfeed your
house, man. Um you know, it's it's
pretty cool. Full kitchen, full bath,
water heater, propane heater, AC, heat,
you know, a little table. Whatever you
want, man. You got mobile internet in
there. Starlink. What else do you need?
I love it. So, but going back to like
what caused you to do this. You said you
were miserable.
How so?
Why were you Why were you miserable?
You ever read the book Song of Solomon?
Well,
parts of it. Not the whole thing.
So,
reportedly the wisest man to ever walk
this earth.
Right.
uh
And to summarize it, it's vanity of
vanities, sayeth the preacher. All is
vanity and grasping at the wind.
Dude, this is what I'm This is If I
could tell y'all any [__] thing and
you heard nothing else tonight, hear
this. In the last 20 years, I have been
from the lowest dregs of society
to the highest peaks and pinnacles. And
it's all [__] smoke and god damn
mirrors, every bit of it. Like, that's
the thing. Guys, making a million
dollars like the Look, you're seeing the
millionaire down
I don't give a [__] Just give me the
van. [__] the van. Just give me the
river.
JUST GIVE ME THE [__] RIVER. I'm so
thrilled to have a van. You know why,
guys? If you cannot learn to be happy
with less, you'll never be [__]
happy.
You only own one thing in your entire
life, one.
It's your body. I don't own this badass
jacket. I'm just using it while I'm
here. And I'm going to die and it's
going to be somebody else's. The only
thing I own is my body. I was born with
it and I'll die with it. Most people
never realize that. They don't give a
[__] about their body.
You slap God in the face. Like
What I'm trying to tell you is my brain
works different, man. And I was here and
I've tried everything.
I've been in three psychiatric lockups,
seen the inside of five jails, three
prisons. I've lived in my mama's
basement. I've been sober in AA. I've
chaired meetings in the mental The same
mental hospital I was locked up in. I
chaired meetings there for four years.
[__] I've won ultramarathons.
I've had a million dollars in the bank.
I've wrapped up in a bed of insulation
to keep from freezing at night. I've
held onto the pylon of a dock while the
police walked on top of it looking for
me, naked in the water. And no matter
where I am, I have the same two fears.
That I will either fail to gain
something that I want or that I will
lose something that I have that I do not
want to give up. It don't matter.
It don't matter. You can take all the
money away, bro. This is it.
And when you figure that out, man, your
life is just different. Like
why am I working like this? Why? Why am
I doing this? Why?
And man, like
I
I ran away when I was 19. I spent years,
years alone with an active mind
reading the Bible and history, which has
a tendency of repeating itself.
And then running up mountains, listening
to [__] like the Unabomber Manifesto.
Like what does that do to a human
psyche?
Right.
Man, I I have to tell you your your
story is
inspirational on so many different
levels from
the mindset of
like tangible things like like you're
talking about your jacket and the band
and the million dollars. Like that
doesn't really matter, but yet you're
still driven
to go out and be successful.
Yeah.
So so what drives you because it seems
like commercial things are not important
to you. So what drives you to be
successful in both real estate and
social media cuz you're killing it. You
just passed 50,000 followers on your
Instagram. Congratulations, by the way.
Look, man. Thank you, man.
I'll be honest, dude.
I'm much happier in a in the woods with
no cell service
and a bag of shrooms and no clothes.
But
and God lets me do that, man, but I'm
here for a reason, dude.
Hey, man. You can't hold lightning in a
bottle, cuz.
Right.
You can't do it. And like that's why I'm
here, man. I've I'm a made man. I could
be sitting anywhere doing anything, but
I'm working 15 hours a day busting my
ass. Why? What a question for somebody
until I I couldn't tell you how much
money I made a calendar year in my life,
and very few people know this, but
except for one small period where I had
to because of some tax election,
I have never drawn a salary of any kind
out of any company I've ever owned,
except $249 a week for a brief period
from Creative Construction. I live like
a pauper, largely without money. I have
I don't eat meat. I rarely take hot
showers.
I don't use an air conditioner. Like,
why am I doing this, man? And literally,
I got on social media for one reason,
man, and one reason only. That if I
could do all these things and show
people that I can invest money and I can
fix houses, I can build solar, I can van
life, dude, I can run up a [__]
mountain. I'll grab a snake. I'm
fearless. They'll respect me, and if
they'll respect me, they'll listen to
what I have to say. All I have to say is
this, guys. America, you need to make
your houses smaller and more efficient
and be happy with less cuz you're
[__] the planet.
That's why I'm [__] here.
And whatever I got to do, dog, as long
as you're hearing them words, that's all
I care about. And you hear them in the
heart, and you see the intensity on my
face when I say them.
And know that yeah, [__] the money, man.
That's why I'm here. And finally, God's
let me get to a place where I'm
somewhere that might be somewhere where
a a lot of people will [__] see it.
And my God, look at my [__] eyes.
America, make your houses smaller and
more efficient and be happy with less
cuz you're [__] the planet.
That's it.
Facts. Let me ask you a question. I saw
on your social media the other day,
someone commented on there about
Well, Joe, the reason why you do this is
because you have money. The reason why
you can invest in real estate is cuz you
had the money. I don't have the money.
Now, I saw your response, so that's why
I'm asking where you were like, "Hey,
you have no idea where I came from."
So, talk to the people right now that
are listening to this
and say, "I want to be just like Joe. I
want to make a difference for people.
Um I I want to make a good living. Want
to take care of my family. I don't want
to live beyond my means, but I just want
to make a living. I want to be in real
estate."
How can they follow and and gain
inspiration from you? What what do you
say to those people?
Step step one, if anybody is trying to
get into real estate on any level, the
first This is step zero.
You need to find a group of people who
are actively making money in the market
in which you're located and put your
shoulder next to them.
[__] a self-help book. [__] I've never
read Bigger Pockets and I got them,
okay? This is what I'm here to tell you.
Just find some people who are doing the
deal. Don't believe the hype.
That's what I'm saying, man. I've never
read a book of any kind. Look at me. I'm
a 5-ft 4 redneck. Eight times If I can
do it, you can do it. Just trust me.
Most people just don't do it cuz they're
scared. They're scared of failure, man.
They have no cojones.
You know, and and and yeah, put your
shoulder next to somebody. Um and the
other thing is you have to audit
yourself.
Like
Some people saying I want to get into
real estate is like me saying I want to
get in the NBA.
All right. Hey, dude. At one point I
tried out for the [__] porn industry
and they told me I was too tall and too
short at the same time, you know?
What do you want me to say? Some people
ain't going to cut the mustard, dog. And
I want to hear you saying that because
listen, I've had a lot of people on here
and it's like they're trying to sell
some sort of education, right? So,
they're like,
"Everybody, anybody can do this, right?
Sign up here. You know,
give me money and I can teach you." And
I've I've openly said it. Hey, man.
Talking to sellers ain't for everybody.
And doing marketing and everything like
that, running numbers, construction
ain't for everybody, you know?
So, I agree with you that real estate
investing is not necessarily
uh meant for every single person out
there just cuz, hey, you saw a show or
you saw Joe Fellows on Instagram and
you're like, "Dude, he was like he's
living a a great life. I want to try
that too." It doesn't mean you got to do
the exact same thing. Now, I got to ask
you about your jacket.
I Well, I want to Let me tell you one
thing real quick. I liken
real estate to the fight game so much
because it's it's very similar. Hey,
guys.
You see these guys on TV and you're
like,
"Oh, I can do what what they do." Dude,
you don't even move like them. You don't
think like them. You have no idea what
these guys do. In fact, you're so
ignorant that you don't even know what
you don't know. And if you stepped in
that ring, the consequences would be
quick and lethal.
And and like yes, and it what they don't
see is the time and effort. And Bruce
Lee nailed it. If you want to be good at
something, do it 10,000 times.
Yep.
So, I mean yeah, dude, yeah, they they
I I'll post it tomorrow. I'm going to
post something tomorrow. You know, this
lifestyle, what I do, real estate, van
life, ultra running, asceticism,
minimalism, these lifestyles are not for
people who want it or who need it. It is
only reserved for people who do it.
And if you want to get in real estate,
really you have to buy a house. And it
is incoming on you to figure out
what the it looks like to get from A to
B based off of honest self-appraisal and
objective thinking.
Yeah.
So.
All right, so this jacket.
You wear the jacket all the time.
And I was going to ask you a NASCAR
question and I mentioned this before you
said you've never watched NASCAR.
I have never watched a NASCAR race in my
life.
So why the hell do you wear a Dale
Earnhardt Jr. jacket every single day?
Cuz it's fashionable as hell.
Who is this?
That's Alex.
Hi Alex.
Hey.
She's
it's fashionable. That's all. I was I
was I was hoping
that since you said redneck real estate
that we were going to be able to talk
NASCAR but you you don't like NASCAR.
No.
I love racing.
But the old-fashioned kind, shank's
mare.
I
I used to run an ultra-marathon every
other month. I ran 50 miles a week. I
love racing but I feel you should do it
the old-fashioned way. I'm not a big fan
of fossil fuels and you know [__] like
that and I love nature. But
I mean I do I don't even like Budweiser.
I just think this jacket's badass. I
bought it off of some
you had to
you showed up and drank a Miller Lite
and wearing a Budweiser jacket.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean but but but let's be
honest RJ. I bought this off of some
dude fixing his moped on the side of
highway 56.
The hey I'll find it. The video's on
Instagram.
Um last year I bought one from a
homeless guy, a badass Georgia jacket. I
literally busted a U-ey
and turned all the way around and pulled
up to a whole gang, probably 20 homeless
people right there in downtown Augusta.
No fear. Walk straight up. What's up,
guys? I want to buy your jacket. I gave
him 200 bucks and then a ride out of
there so nobody else would rob him. And
I gave that to my brother for his
birthday. It was the hard the old
Georgia
before it became the uh
like the politically correct
nice-looking dog.
Right. Yeah.
Yeah, the the old I got
I got you.
For what?
Hate speech.
Oh.
Yeah, yeah, two topics.
I think he said I think he said lethal.
When you said lethal, then it Tik Tok
immediately kicked us off.
All right.
Let me
Yeah, well, it's okay. So, you keep
talking about these ultra-marathons. How
did that get come about because that's
like That's
[__] right there.
And you just Hey, this is what I Were
you always a runner and that's just part
of your life or is that something that
you just
Man, I'll cry about this, dude. So,
man, my
my dad was a uh
My dad was a marathoner, sub-3-hour guy.
Um ran Boston five times and never
stopped at an aid station. This man
could run a marathon in 6 1/2-minute
pace without a drop of water.
And uh loved it, dude. And he just took
a little uh uh a piece of a laminated
paper with a list of names on it and he
prayed for him the whole time. That's
how my dad ran marathons at a sub-3-hour
pace.
That's my Now now now it makes a little
more sense, right? Um
but and he always was on me, all of us
kids. Who's going to do the distance?
You know, I was a wrestler and I played
football. I wasn't trying to run 26
miles. For what, dog? I got a
I got a car.
And uh
man, how old was it? 2000 and
13 maybe, 12, 13, man, he was diagnosed
with Parkinson's.
Couldn't run anymore.
Right now, he can barely walk. I had to
help him wipe his ass a few days ago.
And uh when he was diagnosed, man, we
started run for Mike. My sister did,
man. #runformike
Boy, man, and
Is it okay if I give you a little
backstory?
Yeah, absolutely.
So, my dad was a
a medical doctor, man. He was a medical
missionary in Papua New Guinea. That's
where I was born.
And uh
he never gave a [__] about the money,
man. He was there to help people. And he
had this friend named Jack Loomis in
Rockford, Illinois, who had uh ALS, Lou
Gehrig's disease. And you know, he's
going out quick. And my dad told me the
story about when he visited him.
I'll cry.
When he he visited him, man, he said
Jack was on the bed. And he was always a
big boisterous guy, and he couldn't
move. He was weak. He was He was dying.
He was on his deathbed. And my dad
looked at him and said, "Hey, Jack, if
you could do anything, what would you
do?" And Jack looked out the window, and
it was it was cold and rainy outside. He
said, "Mike, I'd get up out of this bed,
and I'd go run
in that rain, and I'd feel it, and I'd
feel every bit of it."
And
when my dad started losing that, man,
we started running for him.
We did, man. Me and my sister beat the
[__] Marines on their own
obstacle course, dude.
Their own obstacle course.
Um
you know, my sister won a 50K in
Mississippi in May.
I've won two 40s and a 50. My dad was
there for some of these, man. And like,
he was there, and he saw it, man. Catch
him on the hill, son.
Whenever I'm running, man, and I
I feel I feel a cold wind on my face.
Dude, that that's So,
that's that's what happened though, man.
You asked about what changed? My dad,
dude. I was actually running thinking
about my dad, thinking about all this
stuff. The cold breeze on my face,
that's my dad, dude. Anytime there's a
hard wind in my face, it's my dad.
And
And dude, I was running on the road in
Hepzibah, Georgia. I ran a pretty much a
10K every morning, at least. That's just
you know, like you you drinking a cup of
coffee and taking a piss. That's me
running a 10K.
All right. And uh dude, halfway in I had
a massive like running
just running had a massive massive
Damascus road spiritual experience like
that. That was in February. 6 months
later I was in a van headed to the west
coast and my entire life was different.
And it
That's that's kind of it man and I
haven't I haven't run an ultra-marathon
since then. I got injured for the first
time a few weeks later training for the
Georgia Death Race. I tour 10 in three
times and I haven't run one since.
Well, I mean not a race. I ran 29 miles
the other week on the Appalachian Trail
just
came off the couch.
Right.
You know
you shared that story. I'll share a
little bit of mine. You know
I've been an entrepreneur now for 14
years.
Uh officially
started my my first entity real business
like I'm all in started an LLC in 2012.
It was August 6th, 2012.
My dad
watched
Monday Night Football Cowboys versus the
Eagles on September 5th or September 4th
September 5th that night he fell in his
house that he lived in for 30 years and
hit his head never woke up.
Um went to the hospital
um 16 days later he he died. I got woken
up on September 5th and was told
um your dad's having brain surgery right
now.
And uh my son was born
October 19th on my birthday a month
later.
So I started a business
my dad died and I had a son in a 3-month
span.
Really 2-month span 60 days span if you
want to say it. And I always think back
to that moment because I can't really
remember life before that.
And uh
I I share this with you, man, because,
you know, your your dad is
uh you know, not in good health.
But
enjoy every moment that you have with
him right now because
you know
here we are 12 and 1/2 years later, man.
I can't I can't remember many moments.
I'm just being honest with you, man.
Uh
it sucks. Sucks real bad.
And uh
he was my best friend back then.
And now I have a son and he's my best
friend.
And uh
you know
we you talked about being an
entrepreneur and, you know,
make your house smaller, live with less.
I have all these moments that I remember
now with my son.
And I remember
when I started my business, I was so
proud to tell my dad that I was
following in his footsteps as an
entrepreneur.
But
what sucks about that is
is I didn't cherish those memories.
I didn't embrace those moments and at
every person I talk to that I can that
wants to listen to anything that I have
to say nowadays,
I tell them, man, embrace moments.
Embrace moments that you have with
people that you love. You never know.
Um even like this moment right here,
man.
Maybe someone out here is listening
right now, they're going to go tell
their dad they love him.
And it might be the last time they get
to do it.
Um cuz I had no idea.
I was I was a little little punk ass
20-something-year-old.
I didn't think about going and watching
that Monday night football game with my
dad. I didn't call my dad about that
game. Why? Cuz I watched the game and I
went to a dive bar to get drunk that
night doing some Jager shots, cuz I was
about to have a kid. So, I had to get as
many nights in the dive bar as I could.
You know what I'm saying?
I didn't call my dad. I didn't talk to
him about the Cowboys game.
Embrace those moments. Embrace those
opportunities you have, man.
Um appreciate you letting me tell this
story, man.
There hey, thank you for telling me,
man. That's uh that's called a
connection, bro. Like
I can empathize. That's your hero, man.
You know, you've looked up to him since
the day day you were born.
And you know,
you have a kid, too. So, you've realized
I don't know if it ever hit you or when
it did.
When you're changing that diaper, bro,
my dad did this to me. And look and and
and and he's a and look where he is now.
Yeah.
And
like I'm saying, just like everybody who
ever fought Conor McGregor thought they
knew what it was like to fight Conor
McGregor until they woke up.
Right.
When it actually hits you, it's like,
"Whoa, man. Whoa."
Yeah, man. Like hey, let me tell you. I
don't know if you saw,
but uh
it was 2 years ago,
uh maybe three now. I don't know
chronologically, but uh three games ago,
I road tripped to a little place called
Indianapolis with my 70-year-old mama to
meet my brother and sister and watch
Georgia beat Bama.
No way. That's awesome.
Yeah, hey, and my my So, my mama, hey,
she has the ESPN app installed with
notifications. We have a group text. My
mom and my two brothers all college
football season. Hey, golf, uh March
Madness, pro football, college football,
baseball, mama's on it. She drinks beer.
I mean, she's also got a black belt in
American kickboxing and
graduated from Georgia Southern right in
1970. Think Allman Brothers, Statesboro.
She's a gangster. She's a gangster.
Georgia Southern Eagles, right?
And we watch all football games at my
parents' house on Sandy Run Court.
That's where Sandy Run original comes
from.
That's that's awesome. Hey, let me ask
you see Augusta, right? I know Augusta
is Hey, that's where the Masters are. Is
that a Is it Is it as big of a deal to
the people in Augusta?
Hey, make no mistake. We have a
government here in Augusta, but the the
Augusta National like run They run They
run this town.
All right, you know. Hey, get
Have you gone?
Uh-huh, I have, dude. I've been Yeah,
you you know
I don't give a [__] about golf, but I
love the tournament, dude.
Yeah.
They're They're the sandwiches are still
250.
Wow.
The same
The same ladies have been making them
since like the '40s. I mean, and it's Do
they have a Have you ever been?
No. No, it's on my bucket list, dude. I
got to go.
Well, I may or may not have a
Jesus-themed Airbnb
less than a mile from the National.
A Jesus-themed Airbnb?
Right across from Lake Olmstead.
I love it, bro. Hey, is it as gorgeous
in person as it is on TV?
Man, it's
It's a vibe, dog. Let me just tell you,
going to the West Coast and seeing these
old-growth forests taught me about these
vibes. And when you go to the National,
it's a vibe, dude. It's the only place
you'll go in America where everybody is
on their best behavior all all times.
Yeah.
Silent
I got to tell you, if you love it there
and you love the West Coast, have you
ever done the 18-mi drive around Pebble
Beach
in in California?
No, I have not. Yeah.
Now Now, you need to get in your van
and you need to go do the 18-mile drive
around Pebble Beach golf course. You
want to talk about a vibe?
That's You need to look that up,
brother. That's That's a vibe right
there.
18 miles? I just jogged that guy. What
See,
They call it the 18-mile drive because
the drive cuz it's 18-mile circle that
land that you stop at Pebble Beach golf
course, right? But every stop has na-
it's nature, bro. It's
It's got like the the s-
thick sequoias. Um it's got like this
old cypress that's dead, but it's like
growing out of the side of a rock and
it's just it's memorable, bro. You stop
and you just look at these and it's like
this is the only place that you can see
something like this. There's a place
where you stop and there's like
thousands of seals. And they just
they're just there, bro. There's rocks
that are stacked up a certain way and
they don't know why they got It's just
It's crazy. You got to go. It's a vibe,
man. You would love it. It's It's
totally your style, so
Don't worry. I putting it on the list,
dude. And
you can tell I'm an adventurous guy. I
want to go everywhere. Everywhere and
anywhere that's cool, I want to be
there, dude. That's That's my my my
plan. Um
So, do you take requests from fans on
crazy [__] that you'll do in the future?
All the time. And And And I'll be honest
with you, man. I'm really
I really think we're we're working
towards launching just a show, probably
just on YouTube to start.
Yeah.
The Joe Show, man. It It would be so
easy to have 30 minutes of content every
single day. I mean, and and and
literally, like with the premise of hey,
I'm Joe. I find houses with a story all
over the US.
You know,
a creepy farmhouse in my hometown in
Missouri with all the weird deaths,
suicides, and then it caught on fire
twice. You know, like, "Hey, and find
the story and then show up with a band
of traveling van hippies to pimp this
[__] out."
I would Yeah, I do it. So, here's my
request, okay?
So, we started teaching people real
estate. They come in our office, we
teach them. And you know, the big beard,
I would take them ax throwing. I got my
axes back here, right? So, they
nicknamed me the Viking Wizard. So,
that's where the Viking stuff came from.
All right? So, then I I embraced it. I
was like, "All right. You're going to
nickname me a Viking? That's cool." So,
I fell in love with all things Viking.
So, here's my request. You love running.
You said you'll take adventures by
request. You I
Just at some point in time, here's what
I want you to do. I want you to go to
Iceland.
Okay?
Can you go to Iceland?
[__] yeah, as long as it ain't too cold.
And I want you to run around all of
Iceland.
How long is How big is Iceland?
I don't know. Doesn't seem like it's
that big.
You want to talk about 50-mi radius and
[__]
I'm like, dude, like I
I would love to run around Iceland.
Run Run Run from one waterfall to the
next on the Joe Show.
Do they have a trail there?
It's a It's called like the Golden
Circle Road. So, it literally is a road
that just goes all the way around the
whole country.
Well, [__] yeah, Cletus.
Like, dude,
hey man, just call me Joe Gump. [__]
All right. So,
I I got a question. You said the other
day
apparently people call you Joe Dirt,
right? You get that a lot?
I don't know why.
Hey,
yeah, me either.
How do you handle that? How do you feel
about that nickname?
[__]
I'll take as many compliments as you'd
like to give me. What the hell do you
mean?
I love the thing you posted a picture of
yourself and you're like, "Hey, caption
this without using the word Joe Dirt."
Look, I just I am
I just want to meet David Spade. Like,
imagine putting me and David Spade in
the same room for an hour. I mean, with
I just
Come on, man. That would be high
entertainment.
If you've listened this far, send this
to David Spade right now. Tag David
Spade.
Let's get Let's make this happen. Joe
needs to meet David Spade.
David Spade, I think you and I'd get
along. Find a fair amount of things to
talk about. Mm.
I Listen, do
Do you think David Spade's actually a
cool guy?
[__] yeah, man. Look,
so?
Yes.
Dude, that's the thing. Hey, let me tell
you, people who suck cannot play cool
people.
They can't.
I don't know.
I don't But, come on.
I
Listen,
I'm talking about cool people. I I
The Big Lebowski, Jeff Bridges.
Yeah.
That's what I'm saying. David Spade, Joe
Dirt's got to be cool, man. You can't
[__] up my entire childhood, bro.
I mean, that's in the book. Listen,
here's my thing. This is even more of a
reason why Joe needs to meet David
Spade. David, I don't think you're a
cool guy.
I
I I'm I'm Mr. Spade, I think you're
awesome and I would love the chance to
prove it.
Joe Joe wants to prove it to me. So,
right. So, they You need to prove it. I
don't think you're a cool guy. You know
what?
I don't know if I'm asking you on a
date, Dave, or what, but like, I'm
coming, dog. Like, I mean, what's up?
I'll drive my van up. Dude, I'll let you
hang out in the van.
Did you Did you see his uh his movie
Well, you don't watch TV.
Well, I've seen
He had a movie on Netflix a couple years
ago, something Missy, Little Missy or
Missy Calls or something like that.
Uh-uh.
Dude, it was about a from his work that
died
that he wanted, but he wanted another
girl named Missy that was the hot chick.
Okay.
And and and the funny girl that was
crazy, he kept kind of dissing, and that
was the whole purpose of the movie.
But I'm going to be honest with you,
bro. From the get-go, Missy seemed like
she was down for all kinds of monkey
fun, bro.
DAVID DIDN'T SOUND COOL during that
movie. That's all I'm saying.
Well,
[__] Joe Dirt. That was like 20 years
ago.
you would have to have a lot of
uncoolness to undo the coolness bestowed
by this one movie. You see what I'm
saying? Like the shitty Hey, hold on.
The shittiness of the other five or
whatever Star Wars they made has not
diminished the gold of the original
three.
Okay.
Like
I give you that. I give you that.
You know, like
I'll give you that.
That's fair. Yeah.
They lost me at Jar Jar, dog. I mean, if
you were David, if you're really going
to go hang out with Joe, just can you
bring Adam Sandler with you and let me
hang out with Adam Sandler? That's all
I'm saying.
And Jim Carrey?
I have an I have I have an autographed
picture of Jim Carrey. I sent Jim Carrey
a fan letter when I was in second grade,
third grade, and he sent me back an
autographed picture, and I still have
it.
Yes. He did. And it's him and I mean, I
don't know if he signed it or not or I'd
be but I've kept it all these years.
Bro, all I'm saying is is Jim Carrey
and you seem like y'all would get right
along.
Well, all righty then.
All right, bro. So, couple last
questions
before we get out of here. The like to
the people that, you know, truly are
inspired by your story, man,
what what do you have to say to them
about
like taking action and getting started?
Just You said it's just go follow
somebody. Just like
Yes.
Well, if All right, if you if you are at
this There's state There's levels to
[__] If you're at this stage where you
have a concept in your head of I would
one day like to be in real estate.
The first thing you need to do is go
find some people in your area that are
making money in real estate. That's what
I want you to do. Basically,
I Go find the other successful hunters
in your woods and see what they're
doing.
Love it.
Don't Don't you Hey,
and what I'm trying I don't like I'm
sorry if I'm pissing coaches off that
are making a lot of money doing this.
I'm just being honest. Don't find a
one-fits-all book. Find somebody for
your market, dude, that's actually doing
it. And you're not And And what I'm
saying is, guys, go old school. Go old
school. Be an apprentice. Don't find
somebody that you're that's going to
charge you money to learn from them.
What I want you to do is go find
somebody who's doing this, and then you
can go offer your services to them in
exchange for information and training.
Like just say,
"Guys, can I push a broom?"
That kid that I was telling you about.
Oh.
The one that said, "Hey,
you got to interview Joe. He's been
working with me for 3 years. He started
when he was 19 years old."
Justin Helms.
I get I get it.
all about Justin.
I told him the other day, I was like,
"Bro, you will have
20 years experience by the time you're
my age in this industry. How much
further along is he going to be than I
am
when he's my age?"
Just Yes, and people Here's what people
think. Hey, if you're going to make if
you're going to be a nurse,
you got to go to school for what, 2
years at least, to come out and make
$50,000 a year. So, if you would like a
career where you can actively make
figures without working, passive income,
what sort of time commitment are you
expecting to put into this?
Right.
And I want you to This is If you look at
every [__] video I put up, it is
called the reality of blank. Real life
renovation, reality of investing,
reality of travel life, van life. I'm
just showing you the real deal. I'm not
cutting any corners or plan pulling no
punches.
And it's Hey, it's refreshing to have
somebody tell you that, guys. If you
want to get in real estate, plan on 5
years
to doing it. Like just understand, if
you want to get great at something, plan
on putting the time in. If you do not
have this in your schedule, don't do it.
And if you're on the climb up, if you're
already working, whatever, and you want
to get in real estate, before you talk
try investing and making money off of
other people's houses, you need to to to
own your own.
Yeah.
You got to you cuz that's a money leak,
dude. You're you're you're you're
throwing away money that you're actively
earning. Um
you know, in real estate, I was in
investing dividends and returns on
investment all these years. It's the
complete opposite. We want exponential
growth, not uh debilitating leaks.
And so, after that, man, if you're
really trying to go up, man,
you know, uh
you need to get your own living
situation uh debt-free or or free. I'm
not going to say debt-free, but at least
if you're paying a mortgage, you you're
paying into something. And then lastly,
man, you need to
The best way to do this is to get a job
in one of these industries.
I am now a licensed electrician. I got
paid $8 an hour to go to school at Rob's
Electric when I was an eight-time
convicted felon without a driver's
license.
Ding ding ding.
You do that for 2 years, you can go get
your electrical license.
Right.
Okay, that's what I'm saying. You can
get paid to learn. And then you can also
meet learn other things and apply your
trade on the side and you'll have it
wherever you go, man. Like, you know,
your law degree is useful, I guess, but
not during a hurricane.
And also, man,
these are things, you know, I go to
different markets all over the place.
Guys, I can get a job anywhere in the
world, not just America. That's easy,
but anywhere in the world the day I show
up without a [__] application or an
interview. Why? Because I have
real-world skills, people. I can go fix
your house right now, any part of it.
And that's in demand no matter what. All
men, so
all that to say this, equip yourself
with real-world useful skills. Get paid
to learn these skills if you possibly
can, and then learn to get in the employ
of somebody where you can burrow into
the armpit of of a real estate because
it if you don't know anybody, it's hard
to get an in. Like, how do you find an
off-market deal? Everybody sees the
market. How do you find a hard money
lender? How do you find a sub-to deal?
Like, this stuff that's Yeah, dude, it's
like, how do you pick up a hot chick at
the bar that everybody's trying to get?
You either have a lot of money or be
real slick, dog.
There you go. So, you know, you were
during that answer, very extended
answer, I appreciate it. It was
thorough, but
you were you were talking about the
reality of real estate, the reality of
van life.
I think that's where you and I probably
resonate with with our followings and
our audience.
And
I started making a name for myself by
recording my calls with sellers live.
Unedited. So, it was just,
"Hey, this is RJ. See you've got a house
in pre-foreclosure. You looking to sell
that?"
And then, you know, got cussed out, hung
up, picked the phone up, called again.
And I did it for 8 hours a day. And
people were like, "This is insane. I
can't believe I'm watching this. No one
shows this. Everyone edits it. Only
shows
the the good stuff. No one shows the bad
stuff."
And I think that's what you're showing,
too. It's like, "Hey, here's just
reality. Like, you want to do this,
here's the good and the bad, not just
the good." Cuz there there's bad that
comes along with it, too. So, my last
question with you for you, Joe, is
you're very interesting and unique
individual. So,
I have previously asked guests,
"Where do you want to be in 5 years?"
And I just had my 6-year anniversary of
the podcast, and I got to go back to
some of my original guests and actually
share what they said about where they
want to be in 5 years, 5 years later.
So, it was a lot of fun. Ooh. So, my
question to you is,
where do you want to be
I don't want I don't even want to put a
timeline on it. But, what do you want
your future to look like? Like, where do
you want to go from here? Because
you're already kind of doing
what you want. So, where do you want to
go from here?
I- I- If I had my dream,
like my dream, you know, I always want
to travel. That's the thing, I never
want to be set. But, if I had a base of
operations,
and something that I could do,
I would have an eco-lodge in Costa Rica,
Uruguay, like right there on the beach,
man. Like, built out of the jungle,
employing indigenous people at high
wages,
and bringing as many wealthy Americans
to experience a new way of life as I
possibly could.
That's what I would love to do, man. Uh
just, you know, cuando yo estaba en
prisión means me mismo en español. Um
and I would love to go somewhere with
little government regulation where a
[__] can just live
peacefully without being fooled with,
man, and have an echo lodge where people
can come, experience life like I do
because if you live like I do for even a
short period, it will change you
intrinsically as a person.
Um, and I
oh, real quick. I TOTALLY FORGOT
SOMETHING.
WHAT?
HOLY [__] HOLY
RJ, I'M FINE. You can keep me as long as
you need.
Joe, I [__] up the whole interview.
We're going to start over. No, I'm just
playing.
You said you have a hedge fund?
Little one, yeah.
A little one. And you also said you hate
the government, right?
Yeah.
So,
what are your thoughts about this
because I have I've gotten roasted
on the internet on my opinions on this.
TikTok hates me.
Okay?
Washington and Oregon senators
just introduced a bill
to outlaw hedge funds from owning
single-family real estate. What are your
thoughts about that?
You How can you outlaw somebody from
buying a house in the land of the free,
you [__]
It ain't the land of the free anymore,
brother. That's the problem.
I'm here to expose that, dude. Hey, bro,
have you ever comprehended
in the land of the free you have to ask
the government's permission and pay the
money and let them in your private
residence in order to fix your house?
Yeah.
Hold up. Woah, woah, woah. How did we
get here? LET ME TAKE YOU BACK TO A
little time known as 1775
when the British enacted the Quartering
Act and people had to let government
officials in their house and they
started a goddamn war.
That's what I'm saying. Literally like
woah. And what they've done is just
taking a little more and taking a little
more and taking a little more and
nobody's ever stepped back and said,
"Fuck you, man. Get out of my [__]
house." And here's what I'm telling you.
To quote General Jackson, man.
He said, "Well, the president has made
his decision and let him enforce it." If
you look at my criminal record, like
man, look, I ain't I don't know what
your [__] law says. I comprehend a
common sense and you cannot deprive me
of my life, liberty, and the pursuit of
my happiness. And I'm going to do what I
see fit on my land regardless of what
you say. And if you want to lock me up
for it, it won't be the first [__]
time I went to jail, homeboy. Come do
it.
What I'm telling you is during the Salem
witch trials they thought they were
right. And during the Spanish
Inquisition they thought they were
right. And the American government
thought they were right during slavery
too, you [__] [__] And you were
wrong then and you're wrong now. What do
you want me to say? And history always
has a way of reckoning things out. So
you can talk about whatever you want to,
man, but that's a bunch of [__]
dude.
Yeah.
Listen, so what happened is
I've got this show that we do called
Pardon the Disruption where we talk
about trending topics and we have a
minute to answer.
So I got a I got a question about
DeSantis
down in Florida.
Okay, give me backstory because I don't
if you could believe I don't follow the
news at all.
So so here DeSantis down in Florida
said that Chinese citizens
can no longer purchase Florida real
estate. Okay? And the question was what
how do we feel about that?
And I said, "It's a slippery slope. I
don't want the government telling anyone
who can and can't own real estate.
If you don't want a Chinese citizen
owning your real estate, don't [__]
sell it to them.
How about that?
Case in point.
Cuz here's the thing, brother. 250 years
ago
we were ALL IMMIGRANTS COMING OVER HERE
BUYING this [__] okay?
True.
It's not It's not owed to us that we
It's our right to own it. It's our right
to own it if we [__] pay for it.
And you go buy it,
right? And so, I said, I don't want
anyone saying who can and can't own real
estate. So, that was the Republicans.
The Democrats' response was, "Fuck you.
Hedge funds can't own real estate."
Uh-oh, slippery slope starting. Now,
what's going to happen? Now, we're just
waiting on the Republicans to respond.
This is the [__] I hate, dude. I
want the government to stop talking
about real estate. I want them to stop
talking about who can and can't own it.
Hey.
It's our right to own it if we want to
own it and however we want to do it. If
I want to do it inside of a hedge fund,
I can do it.
How about this? Why do we have to listen
to you if you can't even balance a
[__] budget, [__]
Why Y'all are the worst businessmen I've
ever seen. Y'all couldn't think yourself
out of a wet paper sack and you're
working with trillions? Y'all [__]
suck. Hey, like that's what I'm saying.
If If If Hey, if all of America, like
all the working-class regular Joes of
America could send a message to
everybody in Washington, D.C. is this:
You [__] suck on all levels.
All right, hold on. Hold on.
But, Joe, here's the thing. The American
people spoke and said, at least on my
social media,
that they agree with this. They don't
want to
on. But, but, here's Do you know why?
Can I say why? Because the government
pitches it to them like that.
Thank you.
That's why they give it to you.
That's what they said, Joe. They think
that the reason why houses have gone up
in price is because of hedge funds.
Whereas, you and I both know, we've been
doing this for way too long, bro.
How much did a 2 by 4 cost when you
started in comparison to how much it
costs now?
Say less, bro. I say less.
This is the reason why [__] keeps going
up.
Hey, dude. You know what this really is?
This is like silent darts back and
forth. You know what I said, "RJ, can I
give you another plausible scenario?"
The
The Republicans say,
"Well, you know, Chinese citizens can't
buy it." And the hedge funds go, "Hey,
that's a good idea because a lot of
Chinese corporations and citizens are
buying a lot of real estate. And if we
take out these top bidders, da da da."
So, like American farmland.
Right.
Which terrifies the [__] out of me, but
we shouldn't be that dumb, dog. Like,
what do you want me to say? All right.
THAT'S WHAT I KEEP SAYING. PEOPLE ARE
SAYING, "DUDE, we've got a major problem
in Arizona
with I think it's Thailand
is buying a [__] ton of land in Arizona
and and not allowing people in Arizona
to use the water rights that is coming
with this the land." And I'm like, "THEN
STOP [__] SELLING IT TO THEM."
WELL, AND and that's the thing. I see
the the other side pushing back like,
"Well, fine. We're going to introduce
this one. Well, hedge funds can't buy it
either. There goes your lobbyists."
Right.
You see what I'm saying? Like,
but they Nobody's thinking about the
other side. What if I'm a seller and I
have a fantastic deal, but you were
literally depriving me of life and
liberty by telling me I cannot sell my
property to an American citizen just
because he lived in a different country
prior to getting American citizenship?
Right.
What is Is it So, what you're saying is
what you were doing is literally in
essence discriminating against people
from China.
Literally by by definition of the law,
if you're from China, we're going to
treat you differently.
Yes.
I don't know how you can do that nor why
that makes any sense. Like
Or why
the way
the state would want to be like stand
strong on that. I the bro, it's anti
everything that I thought this country
was built on but apparently you and I
are in the the
we're we're the rare breed now day where
we still believe that's a thing.
Right.
Or we want it to be a thing.
I want the government out of my house
for every reason. That like and and
here's the thing. Here's the problem is
that when I say that people now the
mindset is well what are you doing in
there? [__] this is my house. Why do
you I do not have to tell you nor is it
proper for you to even [__] ask. This
is the South.
Yeah.
I mean like dude, this is my private You
know what happens in here? I [__] my old
lady and I [__]
What else do you want to know about dog?
Like [__] man. Hey, if you like
And I that's what I'm saying, man. And
and people they just they go with it
because they're pitched that way, man.
And this is the scary thing to me, RJ,
that it's all in Why do we have building
inspections?
Woo. Woo. Why do we have
There's the there's the theory that goes
out where we want to make sure that
buildings are built correctly.
Correct.
Where we want to make sure that
everything is done up to a code to a
standard so we're eliminating fires,
buildings falling down.
Mhm.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
But if we've ever if you've ever gone
through that process, you know that is
not the case whatsoever.
Well, I RJ, I will challenge you this
because
I had a theory that new buildings are
way
way safer
but also more shittily built than the
other ones.
They are. Absolutely.
Like they're
That's the thing. And when I was
researching this, hey, and I challenge
you or anybody listening, you can email
felzinvestment@gmail.com,
f e l z investment@gmail.com
with any links.
I want an incident of residential
construction being faulty and it killing
somebody in America. I could not find
any. I looked for days.
Couldn't find a single one. I found
commercial, the seaside collapse in
Florida. I saw a a fire at a wharf in
was it California somewhere. I couldn't
find any, not a single one. And like I
found that there were electrical fires.
I think the highest thing I saw on the
CDC website
374 deaths in a calendar year in a
country of 330 million people.
And then of that 42% were simply caused
by people plugging a space heater in to
a circuit that wasn't designed to handle
it. It's user error. So we're literally
talking about like 190 people a year.
And you're making us all buy $70
breakers for this?
What? Dude, that's what I'm What? No,
dude. You're just trying to make me buy
[__] You're not keeping anybody safe,
but what you've done is create a matrix
a book this [__] big on how to build
a house that you can now fee and trap
trap me on and charge me for
inspections, employ a whole bunch of old
washed out contractors who aren't good
for anything else.
And also, now I can come in your house
and see how much it's worth to raise
your tax value.
What? That's all they've done, dude, and
I proved this to myself by going to
Europe. I spent 3 weeks in a van
clandestinely touring old construction
that was built in the 1200s. So far
ahead of this without ever building
inspection. And here's the problem, bro
Cephus. Like these people back then were
building [__] and they weren't bound by
a book. We have literally boxed in an
entire industry. There is no innovation
anymore. You have to play by these
[__] ass rules. Look at the cost of
housing.
Yep.
That's what I'm saying. Like it's
ridiculous. It is so stupid. And the
older [__] is always better, man. From
here to there, man.
I mean I
But Joe, it's hedge funds fault.
Remember?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's hedge funds
fault. Why? Why is it my fault? And why
If I own a house, here's the thing. If I
own a house, I do not see how anybody
But hold on. If I own a house
free and clear
no note
I do not see how any other man on planet
Earth or government entity can tell me
what to do within inside the four walls.
Well, unfortunately, guys, our interview
with Joe Bell was cut short due to the
snowstorm here in Texas. We had a power
outage. So
I just wanted to say hope you guys
thoroughly enjoyed the interview and
thank you to Joe Bell for being a guest
on the Titanium Vault.
Uh blown away by his mindset, his
journey overcoming the trials and
tribulations he had early in life. If
you enjoyed this video, make sure you
like it. If you enjoyed the podcast,
make sure you leave us a five-star
review and we'll see you guys next time
on the Titanium Vault.